Marvel Studios Assembled: The Making of Doctor Strange in the Multiverse
of Madness is a documentary film directed by Brad Baruh.
Join visionary director Sam Raimi and the cast of the film as they recount
their experiences bringing Marvel’s darkest story to life.
From world-building to universe-building, hear first hand accounts from the cast and crew on
what it took to design, create and make each universe unique and believable.
Self - Host / Pizza Poppa, played by Bruce Campbell.
Self - Producer, played by Kevin Feige.
Self - Director, played by Sam Raimi.
Self - Co-Producer, played by Richie Palmer.
Self - Screenwriter, played by Michael Waldron.
Self - Baron Mordo, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Marvel Studios: Assembled is an American anthology television docuseries
of specials created for the streaming service Disney+.
Produced by Marvel Studios, each special goes behind-the-scenes of a Marvel Studios Disney+ series or film, particularly those
within the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU), with the creatives, exploring the process of creating each series or film.
The series was first announced in February 2021.
Marvel Studios: Assembled premiered on March 12, 2021, with subsequent specials releasing
shortly after a Disney+ series' completion or a film's Disney+ release.
14 specials were released for Phase Four of the MCU, followed by 9 specials released for Phase Five projects through
2024, including one for the first season of the Marvel Studios Animation series X-Men '97 (2024).
The special for Agatha All Along (2024) was released for free
on Marvel Entertainment's YouTube channel.
Assembled received positive responses for showcasing how each series or film came
together, particularly with the technical aspects and franchise connectivity.
The film explores themes of superhero, behind the scenes, making of.
The tone is dark.